# Miguel Jimenez

miguel@migueljimenez.co · +57 315-435-2824 · \* \* \* \* /jachinte · \* in /in/jachinte

Experienced software engineer with a strong background in web and cloud development, platform engineering, language engineering, and applied research. Expert in continuous software engineering and autonomic computing.

#### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

# Founder / Senior Software Engineer — Varxen

Aug 2022 to Present | Montreal, Canada & Cali, Colombia

Python, TypeScript, REST APIs, Microservices, Web Development, Full-Stack Development, Architecture Design, Performance Monitoring, Build Automation, CI/CD, Containerized Applications, Terraform, Helm, Kubernetes, Cloud Capacity Planning, Technical Writing

## Senior DevOps Engineer — Edurita

Aug 2020 to Apr 2022 | Victoria, Canada (Remote Canada)

Cloud Capacity Planning , Performance Monitoring , Build Automation , DevOps , CI/CD , Containerized Applications , Kubernetes , Design Patterns

# Senior Software Engineer — Talentum

Oct to Jan 2021 | Cali, Colombia (Contract / Remote Colombia)

TypeScript , Java , REST APIs , Architecture Design , Keycloak (SSO) , Node.js , Loopback , Next.js , CI/CD , Docker , Kubernetes , Helm

# Software Engineer Intern — SAP

May to Aug 2020 | Montreal, Canada (Remote Canada)

Java , JSP , HTML , CSS , Less , JavaScript , Design Patterns , Full-Stack Development , Docker , Hybris , Solr , CI/CD

# Software Developer — Carvajal Espacios

Nov 2015 to Jun 2016 | Cali, Colombia

Java , JavaScript , HTML , CSS , Design Patterns , Web Development , Play! framework (Java) , Spring Data JPA , Hibernate , PostgreSQL

# Software Engineer — Laboratorios LaFrancol

Jan to Nov 2015 | Cali, Colombia

C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Design Patterns, Web Development, MS SQL Server, Node.js

#### Software Developer — SQL Soluciones Informáticas

Jul 2009 to Dec 2012 | Cali, Colombia

 ${\it C\# \, , \, JavaScript \, , \, PHP \, , \, \, HTML \, , \, \, CSS \, , \, \, \, ASP.NET \, MVC \, , \, \, \, Entity \, Framework \, , \, \, PowerBuilder \, , \, \, \, MS \, SQL \, Server \, , \, \, PostgreSQL \, }$ 

#### **PATENTS**

• Two-Way Synchronization of Infrastructure-as-Code Templates and Instances—Patent Reference P202006693US01. Patent Application Filed. Joseph Paul Wigglesworth, Miguel Jimenez, Gabriel Tamura, Hans Albert Muller, Ian Fraser Watts, Hugh Edward Hockett. March 2022. IBM.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Ph.D. in Computer Science

University of Victoria, Canada • Spring 2022

# M.Sc. in Software Engineering

Universidad Icesi, Colombia · Summer 2016

# **B.E.** in Software Systems Engineering

Universidad Icesi, Colombia · Spring 2014

# **SKILLS**

- Technical Skills: Web Programming, Architecture Design, Containerized Applications, Continuous Delivery, Cloud Computing, Infrastructure as Code, Software Deployment, Object-Oriented Programming, Language Engineering, Technical Writing
- Programming and Domain-Specific Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript / TypeScript / Node.js, C#, ShellScript, Xtend, R, C, CSS, HTML, HCL (Terraform), SQL, LTFX
- Frameworks and Libraries: Micronaut, Spring, Hibernate, JAX-RS / JAXB / Jackson, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, Xtext, React.js, Next.js, Angular, Webpack, Babel, Storybook